Guide to the Stanford Humanities Center, Raymond Fred West Memorial Lecture Series, Videorecordings
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford Humanities Center, Raymond Fred West Memorial Lecture Series
1920-2005
SC1072
Stanford Humanities Center.
1 Linear feet (2 boxes)
Collection includes Bernard Knox's 1984 lectures on Psychology; Peter L. Galison's lectures, November 2002, "Poincare's Maps" and "Empires of Time: Einstein's Clocks"; and Lorraine Daston's lecture, March 2005, "Science as Work: Modern Obsessions."
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: tapes that are not VHS will need to be reformatted prior to use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Raymond Fred West Memorial Lecture Series was established in 1910 by Mr. and Mrs. Frederic West of Seattle in memory of their son, a student at Stanford University. The lectures are to promote the subject of "immortality, human conduct, and human destiny."
Description of the Collection
Collection includes Bernard Knox's 1984 lectures on Psychology; Peter L. Galison's lectures, November 2002, "Poincare's Maps" and "Empires of Time: Einstein's Clocks"; and Lorraine Daston's lecture, March 2005, "Science as Work: Modern Obsessions."
Access Terms
Daston, Lorraine, 1951-; Galison, Peter, 1955-; Knox, MacGregor; Stanford Humanities Center.; Lectures.
Collection Contents
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 1
  - Knox, MacGregor
    - "Mythinterpretation/Freudians", 1984 Oct 29; 1.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - "Mythinterpretation/Dumezil and Levi-Strauss", 1984 Oct 30; 1.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - "Mythinterpretation/Levi-Straussians", 1984 Nov 1; 1.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
    - "Mythinterpretation: The Elegant Mythology of the Greeks", 1984 Nov 2; 1.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Galison, Peter L
    - "Poincare's Maps", 2002 Nov 18; 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
      - Use copy, 1.5U; 2 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
    - "Empires of Time: Einstein's Clocks", 2002 Nov 19; 1.6; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
      - Use Copy, 1.6U; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Daston, Lorraine, 2/28/2005; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2)
  - Daston, Lorraine, "Science as Work: Modern Obsessions.", 2005 Mar 2; 1.7; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
- Additional Materials, Series 2
  Materials in this series were previously classified in the Stanford University Publications and Ephemera Collection "4digit" collection.
  - West Memorial Lectures, press releases (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - West Memorial Lectures, announcements, programs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Taylor, Henry Osborn, The Freedom of the Human Mind in History [manuscript], 1920 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - West Memorial Lectures, History (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Moltmann, Jurgen, Human Identity in Christian Faith [bound volume, 2 copies], 1974 Mar (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Angell, James Rowland, The Higher Patriotism, 1938 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ross, G.A. Johnston, Behavior and Destiny: A Christian View, 1931 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)